- [Voiceover] Mystery
Science Theater, 3000,
show 422, 301.
♫ In the not-too-distant future
♫ Next Sunday, A.D
♫ There was a guy named Joel
♫ Not too different from you or me
♫ He worked at Gizmonic Institute
♫ Just another face in a red jumpsuit
♫ He did a good job cleaning up the place
♫ But his bosses didn't like him
♫ So they shot him into space
♫ We'll send him cheesy movies
♫ The worst we can find
♫ La la la
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all
♫ And we'll monitor his mind
♫ Now keep in mind, Joel can't control
♫ Where the movies begin or end
♫ Because he used those special parts
♫ To make his robot friends
♫ Robot roll call, alright, let's go
♫ Cambot, pan left
♫ Gyspy, hi girl
♫ Tom Servo, what a cool guy
♫ Crow, he's a wisecracker
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes
♫ And other science facts
♫ La la la
♫ Then repeat to
yourself, it's just a show
♫ I should really just relax
♫ For Mystery Science Theater 3000)
(doors whirring shut)
- [Joel] Alright, F-stop at 5.6
for maximum depth of field.
Okay, that looks good.
Okay, 5.6, and let's see here, eight feet.
(robots chattering)
That comes to roughly an ASA of 200.
Okay, adjust lighting to
full lumens in a cone.
Focus, that looks good.
Okay.
Bring around the backdrops,
stay cheery, everybody!
Okay, hi, everybody, welcome
to the satellite, hello.
I'm Joel Robinson, and I
just thought it would be nice
to get a nice picture of the
boys to have around the house,
so I'm taking their portrait,
and I'll be with you in a minute.
- Could we just go, please?
- Booger!
- Stop it, you two!
They were like this all the way over!
- You guys, listen.
(Tom hacking up phlegm)
- Cut it out, fem-bot!
- We are going to get
- [Crow] Yeah! Yeah!
a nice picture of this
family if it kills us.
Crow.
- Hey.
What?
- Crow, where are those
nice pants I bought you?
- I don't know.
- You can't walk around
wearing a sport coat
without your nice pants!
- Can we just go!
- [Voiceover] Commercial
side in 10 seconds.
Say cheese!
Okay, now.
Now, come on, you guys.
Shape up, face Cambot.
Come on, Gypsy, get in here.
- Oh, my hair!
- [Voiceover] Hold it.
- Where's the light meter, Joel?
- Oh!
(camera clicks)
(everyone groaning and laughing)
(techno music)
(robots making annoying noises)
- Joel!
- Oh, snicker snack!
- Hey.
- Joel!
- [Crow] Chocolate milker!
- [Joel] You guys,
would you please get back into position?
Come on, knock it off!
(robots tussling)
Gypsy, come on, speed
in chim-chimmer carts.
Stop it!
- Okay, thanks a lot!
Sorry about the tip, I
left the money in my other,
uh, pocket.
Oh! Hi Joel!
How you doing?
We'll be with you in one second.
Clayton!
Here boy!
(kissing noises)
Come here, Clayton, here, boy!
Here, Clayton, here.
- Give me one good reason
(man yelps)
why I shouldn't kill you, Frank.
- Well, the stuff is here.
- Ah!
- The stuff, that we ordered.
- Just in time for the invention exchange.
Uh, you go first, pumpkin pants.
- Well, your ample ones,
(robots bickering)
my invention exchange this week
dynamically blends martial
arts with snacking!
It's called Snacktion,
and it makes snacking fun!
Here's a Snacktion
favorite, the Wax Knuckles!
Alright.
And here's one, it's called a Pixie Staff.
Oh! Huh!
It's a pixie stick, filled
with delicious straight sugar.
See?
Okay, and, uh,
Hey, Crow!
Hey, Crow.
What are these, what are these here?
What are these?
- [Crow] What?
What are which ones?
- What are these?
- Oh, them are the Five
Lady Fingers of Death!
(robots fighting)
- Mmm.
Five Lady Fingers of Death, you get it?
And this is based on a Chuck Norris movie,
it's called the Everlasting
Octa-gomp-stomper.
You get it?
Oh, and these are ninja
throwing cookies.
- [Tom] Oh!
Hey, those are delicious!
- You see everybody
doesn't like something,
but nobody doesn't like Bruce Lee!
Ouch!
- Oh.
I broke him.
- Oh, well, that's really great Joel,
but we've got something going down here
that's really special.
Tell 'em, Frank.
- Well, Dr. Forrester has
taken the money from my 401k
and sunk it into these
fast-food novelty items,
which he's just sold
to a major, major buyer
who shall remain nameless.
- Well, actually that fell through,
but I'm sure they're going to sell.
You see, Joel, they're
called Unhappy Meals.
- You took my money and
you haven't sold them yet?
- Oh, quit whining, Frank.
As an example, Joel, this
one comes from the restaurant
with a cold hamburger sandwich
with a bite taken out of it.
(laughing)
Some floor-sweeping compound,
a couple of dead silverfish,
and a rusty suture needle.
- You took all my money, you son of a...
- Watch it, Frank!
Now, there are many
different styles, Joel.
Uh, for instance, this
one comes with a maze,
and you try to get the motorcade
past the book depository.
And then, this one comes
with a, uh, used Q-tip.
Oh, that is unhappy, isn't it?
And then there's one with a roach motel,
and, well, you get the idea.
Whaddya think?
- I think it's evil and it'll never sell.
- Yeah, give Frank his money back!
- Yeah!
- Oh, blow it out your ex-periment
today is a Swedish fantasy called,
The Day the Earth Froze.
But first, a short, aptly titled,
Here Comes the Circus!
And I hope it goes down hard.
Push the button, Frank.
- No, I want my money back!
- Forceps, Frank. Pain.
- I don't care, I want my money!
- Electroshock, Frank!
- No!
- Push the button!
- [Frank] No!
- The box, Frank!
- Pushing the button.
- [Larry] I'll put you...
That's better.
(siren buzzing)
- We've got movies!
- [All] Aaah!
(doors clanging open)
- Oh, owie.
- I think you broke my toe.
- Here comes the Devil! Hahaha!
- Beelzebub the clown!
- Guys, can we be just a little less dark
with this short, okay?
- Dark?
- [Voiceover] There's
excitement everywhere!
The circus is here!
Everyone is headed for the big top,
to thrill, boo, and cheer the fun-makers,
daredevils, freaks, and
ferocious performing animals!
- And here come the freaks now!
Look at 'em, oh!
- [Voiceover] It's a dime for some candy
and maybe a tummyache, tomorrow.
- Num-num-num-num-num!
- [All] Chug it, chug it, chug it!
- [Voiceover] Peanuts for the elephants.
Now, folks, step right this way
to the bigger, better,
more exciting sideshow!
- Now here's a deal.
Just four years, Christmas present comin'.
- [Voiceover] There's plenty
of time to see it all!
- Get your red hot moms!
- [Voiceover] Your attention,
please, to the lovely
little lady on my right!
- She performs her own tracheotomy!
- [Voiceover] She swallows
a lighted neon tube!
- And she's cute, too!
Heh, ooh!
- [Voiceover] The snake
charmer extraordinary!
On the inside...
- What the hell?
- [Voiceover] The event that
the kids and the grown-ups
have been waiting for for months!
- Nobody's gonna tell a Navy man
when he's had enough to drink.
- [Voiceover] Old Brother
Circus proudly presents
the magnificent and
gorgeous inaugural pageant!
- Oh, look, it's Thomas Edison
with his electric child!
- [Voiceover] And Americana!
(trumpets)
- Support is drummed up for
the Spanish American War!
- Hey, wait a minute,
Aren't the horses supposed
to go behind the band?
- Oops!
- Now make way for the Klu Klux Clowns!
Whoo!
- Yes, children of all ages
are confronted by forces
they can't begin to understand!
- Sig Heil!
- Please, guys, you're too dark,
would you lighten up?
- How bout this, hey look!
It's Roma Clanahead!
- Okay, there, that's...
- It's Ezekiel, the Amish clown!
No buttons.
- Look, it's ice princess zebra!
(Crow fake laughs)
Ah, I like that.
- Hey, it's Emmett Kelly.
- Oh, that's good!
- No, it really is!
- Whatever, Joel.
(robots humming along to fanfare)
- [All] Aah!
- Geez.
- [Voiceover] Empress of
clowns, champion funmaker,
- [All] Aah!
- It's Liza!
(voiceover continues faintly)
- [All] No!
- Razor, no!
- [Voiceover] Aided by
the world-famous funny,
Emmett Kelly.
- See?
Emmett changed management soon after this.
- Oh, we love it when he eats!
- [Voiceover] Introducing Miss Betty Rich,
queen of the air, in a sensational display
of breath-taking aerial feats!
Without the net below,
the first time in America,
Miss Betty Rich!
- Will someone give me a hand here?
- Ooh! Betty got back!
- I'll say!
- It's a living...
- Mother, please come home!
- Yes, our Betty swings both ways!
- Oh, stop it.
- She does, look!
- Listen, you hit the
floor a couple of times,
you make sure you get it right.
- There.
- Ooh!
- This takes care of unwanted
hair in the bikini area.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh!
- Oh, oh, oh, little sting!
- Oh, do that again!
- Ah, they take a licking,
and keep on kicking!
- Women that love too much,
and the feet that use them!
- This one's on the rebound!
- [Voiceover] And now, the only girl to do
a complete somersault, too high,
to the feat of the balancer.
- This act was outlawed
on several continents!
- Yes, it's the man who
mistook his wife for a hat!
- Hi, Rick!
- Sarah.
- Flipped her off.
- Sorry, Wayne, this
is for the ladies only!
- [Voiceover] The
celebrated Ryfenoff troupe,
bareback-riding marvels
whose equals do not exist!
Base and beauty of equestrianism!
- Turn your head if you're squeamish!
- Yes, this act embodies
the sadness that is circus.
- That is too dark, Tom, stop.
- What? Sorry.
What, what?
- Is all he does is eat?
- It's fun, he's good at it.
- What?
- [Voiceover] The beautiful
bareback riding ballerina,
Miss Lucy!
- Could not be with us tonight,
so we have this act.
- You're next up there!
- [Voiceover] And now, ladies
and gentleman, we present
- Woo!
Ooh, hoho, ho ha ha!
Whoo! Oh!
Whoo! Huh haha!
Whoo!
- I thought there was another bar!
- Oh!
- [Voiceover] Here come
the comics of the air,
adventurers and hilarious feats
high above the sand bar!
- Store this image away
for a later nightmare!
- I invented that move.
- Yeah right.
- Levi's loose-fitting clown jeans.
- Huh?
- Oh, no, no, no!
They're doing it clown style!
No!
(Crow laughs)
- And Madonna thinks she's innovative!
- Oh, please tell me this isn't happening.
Oh, no.
- More, more, I'm a bad clown!
- Yes, children's windows
of perception are opened
for only a second, only
to take in the horror
that is the Circus.
- High above the crowd,
Dag Hammerskoljd takes to the trapeze!
- Yes, it's Albert Speer
nude, donning a dance belts!
- Ooh!
- Thank you, Albert.
- [Crow] Woah!
- [Voiceover] In the center ring,
the only group of Pamolino
liberty horses in the world!
Trained and presented by Adolph Del Bas
- We won't linger on this one, folks!
There's not much to it, really.
- Did you remember to punch in, Ed?
- Neigh!
- Oop, that is Siegfried!
- Over here, Roy!
- Hello, Siegfried!
- Hello, Roy!
- Ya, ya!
- This is a Freudian dream!
- Hey, kibble's brought in.
- Hey, Mr. Douglas, I see you got a horse.
Well, it's not really a
horse, it's more of a...
- Oh, fellas, this is just wrong.
- [Voiceover] On the Hippodrome track,
high-jumping horses!
- Oooh!
(Crow laughs)
- And Emmett Kelly's still eating!
- And it's still funny!
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
- [Voiceover] And now,
the most daring rider
in all the world, Miss Dorothy Herbert,
blindfolded over a barrier of fire!
- Oh, it's Blackened
Beauty, the Cajun horse!
- Hey, C. Everett Kook!
(robots humming)
- [Voiceover] Presenting Abhab and Freddy
for the funniest prize
fight in circus history!
- Bing Crosby's relationship
with his son Gary
is re-enacted!
- Hohoho, let the nightmare begin!
- This is the strangest debate
format I have ever seen.
- You know, don't laugh, but in a way,
this is this town's passion play.
- Oh.
It's a full-contact Who's
Afraid of Virginia Woolf!
- Don't talk about our clown, Martha.
- Kitties!
- Meow.
- [Voiceover] And now,
Sly Petey, the most fearless
man in all the world!
Alone in a cage with a herd
of man-eating African lions!
The greatest wild animal
trainer of all time!
- Is not here!
- [Voiceover] For the
most ferocious of all
jungle-bred animals!
- John Tuturro?
- Stella!
- [Voiceover] The Six Flying Brothers,
daring to dare marvels
high over the center ring!
A proof of absolutely
fearless and unrivaled
- Looks like an ant farm.
- [Voiceover] Writhe
through the air performing
spectacular and hazardous feats!
- I know, you're not gonna
complete fifth-grade gym
without doing this, right?
- Come on, lemme hit you on the butt!
- No!
- How 'bout just a light tap?
- Uh-uh, not now!
- Oh, come on, please, right now!
- Well later.
(robots bickering)
- You're ruining it for me!
- Stop it.
- What?
- Sorry.
- Pass the word, Ed's been
hitting the bottle today!
- Oh, like that's a big improvement
over what we've been doing.
- Party in Susan's dressing room!
- Already in Sarah's dressing room, pass.
- Uh-oh!
- [Voiceover] Miss Jean Ellen,
with a herd of ponderous pacoderms!
- Speed Elm?
- [Voiceover] Their
trunks full of new tricks!
- A rogue elephant snaps its
tether and kills a coolie!
- Now who's getting dark?
- I like it!
- I'm taking this elephant
for a test drive, ooh-hoo-hoo!
- Three elephants and a little lady.
- [Voiceover] The circus
with its thrills, fun,
sawdust and spangles, brings
joy and merriment to everyone!
- But me.
- [Voiceover] Here Comes
the Circus is always
a memorable event.
A truly great and carefree day for all,
from six to 60!
- Do you think she's
working for peanuts too?
(all laugh)
- Oh, she enjoys this a little too much.
- Um, don't blow any water right now!
- Oh, my favorite part of the circus.
(techno music)
- Oh, wait a minute,
how can something be
American and international?
- Let's watch and find out, shall we?
- Oh, cripes, I remember that day.
- Oh yeah, you've gotta dress for it.
- Oh, ya hey, the temperature
got all the way down
to about 14 below zero!
- You don't know the half of it!
- No, Pearl had to jumpstart
the Chevy that day.
- Oh, ya hey, the snow was yay high,
and you'd come up the
back way after, ya know?
- Course I don't know nothing about that.
- Oh, no.
- Then we seen where all
the schools was closed.
- Oh, yeah.
- Course the kids enjoyed that
part, that was real, yeah.
(everyone agreeing)
- It was just like the winter of '75,
when it got down to 30 below.
- Oh, yeah, but when you
consider the windshield,
you know, when it's about 100 below.
- Yeah, and you know, it
was a good thing I had
the snowmobile suit for to run
over by Evelynn's house here.
- Oh, sure, yup, yup.
- It was just so ding-dang cold,
I'd go outside, the stuff in
my nose'd just freeze right up.
(laughing)
- Ah, the standup movie in sketch.
- [Voiceover] Throughout
history, people have listened
to the storyteller.
- Against their will.
- [Voiceover] Men who could
fashion myths and fairytales,
make them live for his mysteries.
- Sid and Marty Croft?
- [Voiceover] Such men
were the Brothers Grimm
- in Germany.
- [Tom] Oh.
- [Voiceover] Hans Christian
Andersen in Denmark,
and such a man was Elias
Lonnrot in Finland.
- Here he is on vacation.
- [Voiceover] He wrote the
story you are about to see.
- [All] Ah!
- [Voiceover] Long ago,
- [Joel] They're golem!
- [Voiceover] in a faraway
place called Kalevala,
there was a village of fisherman.
The land they lived in
was large and beautiful.
- As were the women.
- [Voiceover] It was blessed
with the great rivers
filled with fish.
Wonderful forests with tall trees,
- And pollution from the
nearby paper processing plant!
- [Voiceover] And the
people toiled very hard,
- Hey, this is hard!
- [Voiceover] For they had been promised
that if they worked
the Earth and the seas,
- Bye, Grandma!
- [Voiceover] one day they
would be given as their reward,
- It's a documentary?
- I'm here for the
Prince Valiant auditions.
(Joel sings)
- One, two, three,
I can't fall asleep countin' those guys!
- They're goats!
- Oh!
- [Voiceover] And salt.
Such was the magic of the Sampo.
- What?
- [Voiceover] Now it so
happened that the Ilmarinen
had a beautiful sister named Annikki.
- She was tender and young,
- [Joel] Annikki in the U.K.?
and spent her days happily
- wandering in the forest.
- [Crow] Your mother is
long dead.
- [Voiceover] All the
people of the village
loved her dearly,
- Hey, there's Burt
Lancaster, Walter Pidgeon,
Robin Givens!
- Chickarea!
- [Voiceover] That would be
sign, that the time had come.
- For democracy!
- [Voiceover] That Sampo was to be born.
- Escape to Wisconsin.
- Ever since Annikki had
become a young woman,
she remained by herself,
and refused the attention of any young man
who brazenly thought he might seize her.
- Look at that! It looks
like Penny Marshall!
- [Voiceover] One man she had never met.
- Gary Big Nerd!
- [Voiceover] He lived deep in the forest.
His name was Lemminkainen.
- Wine, Lemminkainen.
- [Voiceover] He was a woodsman.
He was young, and simple.
- And practiced
slash-and-burn agriculture.
- [Voiceover] He worked hard,
- [All] Woah!
- [Voiceover] but was
never noticed at all.
But there was something about him
that would someday, sooner
than you would think,
- Oh, there goes the last spotted owl.
- [Voiceover] save the
village from the most
horrible, cruel misfortune
it would ever know.
- The Reagan-Bush administration.
- [Voiceover] For these
good people did not realize
that all the time they worked the Earth,
- Has anyone seen Timmy?
- Tim, oh no!
- [Voiceover] A witch
plotted against them.
- Hey, check it out, it's
Sting, and David Lee Roth,
and Peter Noonan, Sammy Hagar,
and David Carradine, and,
Santa?
- Why don't you use an axe
on your hair, you hippie?
- For three days, your
mother has not seen you,
Lemminkainen.
Go home and take a rest.
- And take out the garbage,
and help your mother
clean the garage, for crying out loud!
- From the land of sky and water...
- Water!
Hey, check out my log.
I got it for graduation.
- Heh, it's my cigar boat.
(all laughing)
And a river runs through us.
- Yes.
- Hey, get me, I'm making
an Mountain Dew ad!
- Let's go surfing now,
even Sven's learning how,
- If everybody had a spruce
tree, across Finlandy ya!
- I wish they all could
be Norwegian girls!
- Hey, anybody call a cab?
- The adventures of Fjord Fairlane!
(all laugh)
- Uh-oh, rush hour!
- Now, wait a minute,
let me get this straight.
Abba's gonna pay me to surf?
- John Houston's The African Log.
- White hunter, black heart.
- Damn, crazy Swede!
- Ancient Swedish secret, huh?
- My baby takes, huh?
Wow, look at that laundry!
- Ah, hahahaha, ha.
- Hey, I'm gonna go play
mini-golf at Cross Lake,
you wanna go?
- She's washing her Christo!
- Don't walk on my laundry, Steve.
- Yes, may I help you?
- Whose gold is that?
- Mine.
- [Leninkainen] Could this be the daughter
- of the rosy god?
- [Tom] Agent Mark,
he's just pulled up in a log!
- [Lemminkainen] Of the
radiance of the moon?
- It's not the moon, nor is it the sun!
I'm just a (indistinct)
- You can say that again.
- Annikki is my name!
- Poker's my game!
- [Leninkainen] Annikki?
- I went to school with your brother!
- Hey, my other log's a redwood!
She's got a gun!
- [All] Ah!
- If you don't like the way I'm driving,
call 1-800-Bite-Me.
- Well, it was nice meeting you!
Lemminkainen, was it?
(mooing)
- That was weird.
- Do you want to be Finnish?
Sure, we all do.
- Poppies will make us sleep?
- They're tulips!
- Oh.
(robots ribbiting)
- Ah yes, my little chickadee!
- Hey, what's the pecking order here?
- She's got an amazingly
dull life, doesn't she?
- Ah, dinner!
- Oh, no, after you!
- No, after you, I insist!
- No, I insist, age before beauty!
- Pwn!
- Eh, hello, Boo-Boo! Mmmhmm!
- John Irving wrote the screenplay.
- Ilmarinen!
- Uh, busy!
- Annikki!
Sister of mine.
- You shaved your beard!
- What's the matter?
- Oh, my dearest brother!
His eyes sparkle like the sunlight
shimmering on the sea foam!
- Oh, hohoho, aw!
(doors closing)
- [Crow] Yes!
- [Tom] Great!
And then we swing back
and forth on the high wire
while furiously spanking each other!
- Great! I love it, it sings!
It's got legs, it's got...
- [Tom] Ah, it's magniferous!
- Alright, listen, you guys, please.
Remember I said I'd type in your ideas
for a clown act, alright?
I find what we're talking about here
just a little bit
derivative from what we saw
the clowns do in the short.
I think you should think
of your own ideas, okay?
- Well, we're not paying you to think!
Just take all those down
as we dictate it, Peggy.
- Okay, where were we?
Wait, I've got it!
We're on a trapeze,
- Yeah?
- And you hang,
from my tongue!
- While I drive sheet metal
screws into your eyes!
I love it!
- It's good, I admit that,
but maybe we gotta work
more butt in the act.
- Wait!
I've got it!
- Yeah?
- I grab you and squeeze
you till you hemorrhage.
- No!
How about I come out
dressed like a suture,
you come out dressed as an appendix?
- Eh, you're a P in appendix,
if you know what I mean.
- Uh, fellas, can I remind you,
you're gonna be clowns in a circus.
There's gonna be kids watching.
- Can I just remind you to bite me?
Now, get back to work, Della!
- Wait!
I've got a brilliant idea!
- Okay.
- This routine starts out normal,
you and me beating the
crap out of each other.
- Yeah, yeah.
- [Crow] Then I snap!
I run into the audience
on a homicidal rampage!
- Yes!
Then I appear playing the part of Death!
Funny Death, of course.
- Hey, you know what
would be really funny?
- What would be really funny?
- If we could somehow
make the audience members
question their love for their spouses.
- Yes, and here's the topper!
We convince all the kids in the audience
that they were adopted!
- Ah!
- Alright guys, listen.
I knew you would take
something like the circus
and turn it into some
dark carnival of the soul.
- Listen, Joel, for your information...
(typewriter clacking)
- Hey!
You didn't take down a word we said!
You had Cambot program a typing effect!
- You were just toying
with us, weren't you?
- That's right, and you know why?
- Why?
- Because there's a little
bit of the clown in all of us.
Goodnight, and may God bless.
- D'oh!
- Aaah!
(techno music)
- Oh, come on, I couldn't resist!
- This is before unions.
Let it be a lesson to you!
- Hey, Tom, could you punch out for me?
- I'm not going into early retirement!
- Ron Wood on any given morning.
- Oh, come for the fire, soul.
- Come on, a tour's coming through here,
get to work!
- How much longer do you expect me
to put up with your absurd show?
Can't you make a Sampo?
You call yourselves wizards?
- We've done the best, the labor's...
- Cast him into the viper's pit!
- Ah, bein' clean, Ma'am.
- Let the snakes devour him!
- Can't you just dock me?
- No, Mistress, I beg of you!
I know of someone who
will be able to help you
build your Sampo!
- [Witch] Who?
- Murray on third shift!
- The fortuned blacksmith, Ilmarinen,
in the land of Kalevala!
He is the only one who
knows the right way!
- You!
Have longed boasted your power
over the secrets of nature!
I demand that you show me now,
the face of this Ilmarinen!
- Mm, let's go check the files, honey.
- Hehe, don't know what I'd do
without my right-hand troll.
- Gesundheit, gesundheit, gesundheit.
- Ilmarinen, come before us.
Ilmarinen, stand before us.
- Oh, they're Pentacostal.
- Ilmarinen, come before us.
- Ilmarinen, stand before us.
- [Joel] Posture.
- Stand before us!
- It's leaking!
- Ugh!
- Ilmarinen, stand before us.
- Ilmarinen, appear!
- Help me, Obi Wan, you're my only hope.
- Hey, don't sit so close to the set,
you'll ruin your eyes.
- I have fashioned a bracelet for you.
- It's a padlock!
- Annikki?
- No, Precious Moments.
- And she's Ilmarinen's sister!
- Oh no way, I thought she
was Joanie Coslack's brother.
- High ransom will he pay
for his pretty sister.
- I wonder what kind of name
Lemminkainen is, Italian?
Irish?
Lemminkainen, very pretty, haha!
I made a joke.
- Go on swift wings to
the land of Kalevala!
- For one hour, modernising!
- To the foreign Annikki.
If you find her alone,
bring her quickly back!
So that she may become my prisoner!
- Well she's one sheet to the wind.
- Wait a minute, I forgot something, oh!
- Grandma's been talking
to the bedding again.
- You really get a lot of
use out of a good wool cape.
- We'll be cruising today at an altitude
of about 60 feet or so.
- Well, let's see now, what did she say?
Go to something, and get something, uh,
from, yeah.
- Please remain seated until the cape
has come to a complete stop, thank you.
- Hmm?
Oh, don't tell me
Hercules is in this movie!
- Hercules is in this movie.
- Oh, I asked you not to tell me that!
- Oh, the cabin boy, the cabin boy,
the dirty little birdie!
(hums)
- Hey, uh, how'd I do that?
- Boy, kidnapping was
really easy back then!
- Oh, Popeye!
- He's large.
- Dun, dun, dun, huh?
The hell?
- There's a roast in the oven!
I don't know when I'll be back!
- Oh boy.
- The secret storm!
- Da weather started gettin' rough,
- [Robots] the tiny ship was tossed!
- There's a flash flood warning
affecting Stonehenge region!
- By the pricking of my thumb,
something goofy this way comes.
- Come on, doggy.
- Geez, thanks for the lift!
- Call the front desk
if you need anything!
- I got one!
- Hey, get me, I'm Swedish
and I've got rhythm!
- I sing whenever I sing!
- Ilmarinen!
- It's three in the morning!
- The evil witch Louhi
has stolen your sister!
- Yeah, and?
- Annikki!
- Here, wait a minute,
let me put my sword out.
There.
- Give me the sword!
I will go to Pohjola!
- Ah, let me just finish up here.
So there!
Say hi to my sister!
- I will go with you to
Pohjola, Lemminkainen!
- Wait, I'll drive.
Let me get my keys.
There we go.
(hums)
- Vainamoinen!
My sister has been stolen!
- Well, was she insured?
- By the evil witch, Louhi!
- Looks kind of like a Bible story.
- Tell us, Vainamoinen!
Tell us how we can find our way
to the misty shores of Pohjola!
- Go down to the third stoplight, and...
- Ah, Pohjola, the edge of the world.
If you want to go there,
- Take the Santa Monica freeway.
- It will carry you over
the waves like a white swan.
- Tell us, mighty one.
How can we build a boat such as that?
- I'm glad you asked.
I'm having a boat-building seminar.
- In this ancient oak tree
you will find your boat.
Whereupon you take it
out, and it will carry you
across the sea to the shores of Pohjola.
- Okay, how much is
this gonna set me back?
- Oh, I'm a-chafin like me!
Oops, did it again.
- You're kidding me, a boat in here?
- It's a chip-away game.
- Is there another wise
man we could talk to?
- Eight years later...
- So anyway, that's what
really got me interested
in stamp collecting.
Of course, I've always loved the theater.
- Just shut up.
(tree creaking)
- Hey, no boat!
- That's my scratching tree, you jerks!
- Not that tree.
(stifling laughter)
- Ah, Fred, did I mention
that I have a boat?
Oh, now they're just showing off.
- Oh, now what did they
chop the sail out of?
- Oh, they cut the wood real thin.
- Uh-huh.
- May the sun light the way to
bring you safely home again.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, can
the balloon juice, Gramps,
we're out of here.
- Hey, shouldn't we
patch the bottom first?
- I just pray there aren't no portages.
- Oh boy.
The Stay Puft Marshmallow Man in chains?
- Kinky.
It's giant sweet breads.
- It's body wars.
- Someone has come to visit us!
- Quick, pick up the place!
Make yourself presentable!
- [Male voice] Over here!
It's me!
- What, it's a bag of Homer Simpson?
(all crying out)
- Wait, one at a time, please, come on.
- [Woman] Yes!
I am the South Wind!
- Do you provide a service of some sort?
- [Male Voice 2] And
I, I am the East Wind!
- Put your teeth in, I
can't understand you!
- Are you the North Wind?
- I am the Mists.
- I'm relative humidity.
It's not so much the heat as it is me.
- I'm the summer wind
that come blowin' in.
- And you!
(giggling)
Which one are you?
- Oh me? I'm just the laundry.
- I am the North Wind.
- Call me Sandy.
- I was born among the ice.
- Oh, that's fine, thank you, heh heh.
- Please let me out!
- Yeah, I didn't ask for a biography.
- Very well, I will let you out.
- [Louhi] So, this is where I find you!
- Oh, we weren't kissing,
we were just talking!
- It's something to amuse you.
Just come with me, I'll
find something for you.
- I've got one of those little pool tables
I bought at Brookstone.
- Hold my prisoner in chains!
- Alright, some orders we like to get!
- Let me go!
(techno music)
- Deep thoughts.
- Oh, Walleye Chop!
I'd better get out there!
- Eric's small cigars.
- Inconceivable!
They're gaining on us!
Oh, the keg's here!
- Aye, he has come, as I said he would.
Do you see his boat approaching our shore?
Do you hear the waves bringing him nearer?
Come, wake up!
Run to the beach and welcome him!
- You're the boss, you're
the queen of everything, ok.
- Smiles, everyone, smiles!
- Hey, do you have a dock or something?
We'd really appreciate it.
- Huh, look at that boat.
What, did you carve it out of a tree?
- Shut up, shut up!
- [Wizard] Mistress!
Oh, you were right!
The boat is bringing Lemminkainen,
and his friend, the immortal blacksmith,
Ilmarinen!
- Greetings for all!
Who accepts the challenge
that I have brought?
- Can't, got a bad knee.
- I did the last challenge.
- I have come to free the maid Annikki!
I am here with her brother.
- Uh, Tony.
- You are no coward.
- No coward?
- Then fight!
If your power can protect
you from my arrows.
- Yes, my power is great.
- Ah, it's not that fun
- [Louhi] Magics!
going to Grandma's anymore.
- And charms.
And terrible spells
enough to drive you back
into the boiling cove
from which you've come,
you blundering fool!
- That's enough of that.
Do you imagine we've come here
to listen to an old woman raving?
- That's why most people come!
- Now, do you accept the challenge,
or will you give up my sister without it?
- Take the curtain, go for the box!
- I will not give up Annikki.
- Here she busts, the witch is brittle!
- No, wait!
- Let me take off my girdle!
- I will give your maiden back to you,
if you perform two simple tasks.
- Aw, this bites, let's blow.
- What tasks?
- Pick up my dry cleaning
and call the vet.
- I have a field overrun with snakes,
and he must first plow it!
- Alright.
- It's weird, but...
- Show me where your field is.
- Come on, come on, good Lemminkaimen.
- Don't wait up, Eric,
if you know what I mean.
- Say, that is cold.
- You see it before you.
- You see an old grackle.
- A field of snakes.
- Hey, Kevin Costner's in that, isn't he?
- No, this is the dirty version.
- Oh.
- I want a plow.
And I must have a powerful horse with it.
- Nay, I'm the cursed boss here.
- Are you asking me to feed
one of my horses to those snakes?
- He needs a horse.
I will build him a horse.
- Oh, make it out of a tree!
- Horse chestnut.
- [Wizard] Oh, Mistress!
- Don't call me that in public!
- Come here!
You must not allow Ilmarinen
to build that horse!
He'll be sure to plow the field,
and they will take Annikki!
Ilmarinen will refuse to make us a Sampo!
- Have patience!
He won't be able to carry her away.
- Now, slip into that stable boy suit
and meet me later down by the...
(whispering, laughing)
- Mistress of mine.
(men yelling)
- Oh, wow.
- And the sculling crew takes to the lake!
- We've got to get organized!
- [All] Attica! Attica! Attica!
- It's the Oslo riots!
- Hey uh, that's not very
smart when you're in the boat.
- He is pounding the air there.
- That's an air hammer.
- Ooh!
- Hey, we're going over
to Sven's after, huh?
Want to?
- Hmm?
- Suddenly it's flash dance!
- He's a steel town Sven
on a Saturday night!
(hammer thudding)
- Okay, okay, if he can make a horse,
why'd he have to cut that tree down?
- Yeah, well, now I just sit back
and rake in the praise, pretty much.
- Ooh, Daddy, ooh!
- The Tri-star logo's ready!
- He's...
Safe!
- They ran calling wild-fire!
- Ooh!
Ouch, ooh, stingy, that's still hot!
- Tsst, haha, tsst!
- Hello, I'm from the temp agency,
I'm your horse for the day!
- Ooh, must be the plow.
- Hey, good timing!
Boy, we work good together!
- Could you rub some
Solarcane on me, please?
- A horse?
We didn't plan on that!
- Will someone please turn the Wagner off?
- Hey, I think he just
invented the Mobile logo.
- Hmm!
- Yech!
Kind of a goofy Scandinavian double-dare.
(men yelling)
- Oh, man, it's a puppet, look.
- He's being attacked by a woozle.
- Yeah, they're, they're
all yelling, "Fake!"
- And now, I'd like to do my
Nostowsya Kimski impression.
I'll just take off my clothes.
- I knew they'd worm
their way into the film.
- You know, I wonder if that horse
comes in any other colors.
- Well, he's the enemy,
but you gotta admire him.
- Yup, yup, tip your cap.
- Hey.
Get a look at this, huh?
- Now let's go in and see
if Mom's got dinner ready.
- Oh, great, we can plant more snakes now.
- Alright, I've finished
plowing your field.
- Planted now with care.
And may the grain grow
as high as my shoulder.
- Now where is she?
We want to take her back!
- I'll give you your Annikki,
but it won't do you much good.
There isn't very much left of your boat.
- Hey, that's below the belt.
- Yeah, I don't really get witches' humor.
- Come along, let me show you!
- Brother, she's got issues, huh?
- It's the Swedish dells!
The Dukes ride the Dukes.
- Hey, you wrecked our boat,
you freaked-out maniac!
- [Louhi] A great fish
swimming near the shore.
It flipped its tail once,
and smashed your boat!
- Well I suppose those
kind of things hap--what?
- Then I will make a new boat!
An iron one!
And tell your fish if he
tries to smash this one,
it'll break his teeth off!
- Well, you don't have to yell.
- Huh?
(Ilmarinen chanting)
- They're roasting Bullwinkle!
- Come forth!
- Feed me, Rocky, help me!
- Again?
- Oh, nobody ever helps this guy.
- Look! A boat!
(all crying out)
- Uh-oh! Out of control.
- What's going to become of us now?
- Oh, everything's about you, isn't it?
- When log float rides go horribly wrong!
- You may get burnt on this ride.
- Uh, there's a flaming
moose blocking traffic
on I-35, W, Northbound.
- Would somebody please put me out?
I seem to be on fire!
- Protect us!
- Have mercy, dear mistress!
- Do something!
- Now, there's something you
don't see every day, Chauncy.
- Yeah, what's that, Edgar?
- KISS going bass-fishing.
- Quite a boat, wouldn't you say?
- Now that it's finished,
we'll be on our way,
the minute you give us Annikki.
- I demand that you make your boat stop!
- When you release my sister!
Your only excuse before was because
your fish wrecked our other boat!
- Ah, point well taken.
- You act like I'm the bad guy!
- I don't know if your
sister is ready for that.
- She's still upstairs dressing!
- I warn you, lady of Pohjola!
You better give us Annikki!
- Only he has performed
well what I gave him to do,
and you, what did you do?
- Yeah!
- I've heard you make magic too!
- Hell, I made the horse!
- What are you talking about, what magic!
- I mean, the Sampo!
- [All] Dun dun dun!
- Have you anything in you heart...
- Forge a Sampo!
Or you'll never see the face
of your pretty sister again.
- Can we see the other parts?
- Crimeney, better look up Sampo quick,
I think she's serious.
- [Ilmarinen] Louhi,
I'll do anything you ask,
- Only a Sampo!
(techno music)
- No, Tom, you're thinking of a sample.
S-A-M-P-L-E.
We're talking about a Sampo, with an O.
- Oh.
- Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
So if a Sampo isn't a small
taste of no-fat cheese
at the grocery store, then
what, I implore you, is it?
- [Crow] Well I was
thinking that maybe a Sampo
is a really good can opener.
- [Tom] No, I think it's
a strapless evening gown!
- You think everything is
- I just think they're neat, is all.
What do you think, Joel?
- Uh, I think a Sampo's
like a hand-hammered
conch belt with turquoise inlays,
used to accentuate an oversized blouse?
- I think it's that dent
between the nose and lip.
- Well, whatever it is,
that witch wants it more
than anything, so it must be
some sort of wrinkle cream.
- Oh, no, I got it.
Sampo: A progressive new corporation
with an eye towards the future.
Sampo is a corporation
for people, by people.
- I think it increases corn yields.
- I think it's a nasty
little rubber novelty item,
if you know what I mean.
- Well, maybe it's not tangible.
I mean, maybe Sampo is found
in the laughter of children,
or in the roar of the tide,
or in the capacity to love and be loved.
- No, I know.
I think Sampo is a new
high-energy prop comic.
You know, like, "Ladies and gentlemen,
"The Funny Bone is proud to
present funny man Sampo!"
- Well, one thing's for sure, gentlemen.
The US of A still makes
the best damn Sampos
on the market, and I mean
nobody is going to change that!
- I've got it.
It's fresh, it's sassy,
it's free, it's me!
It's an exciting new fragrance
by Prince Machipelli!
- Oh no.
- Maybe not.
- Well, to be honest, everybody,
we don't know what a Sampo is.
- Not a clue.
- If you know what a Sampo is,
write it down on a piece
of paper, throw it away
and then try not to think about it.
You'll be glad you did!
- [All] Sampo!
(siren buzzing)
- Oh, movies!
- We've got movies, oh, let's go!
- Sampo!
(doors whirring, clanking open)
- Ding! Sampo up!
- Oh, geez, what a day.
- You know, I really
admire how you stood firm
on the Sampo issue, your witchiness.
You didn't give an inch,
and I really admire that.
- We'd like to show you how
we maximized the warehouse
to increase Sampo shipments!
- Yes, it's really exciting.
I think you should come
and take a look at it.
- Well?
- I must have a wisp of lamb's wool,
a feather from a swan,
and a barley corn!
- You hear this guy?
- Get him the smallest of the flock,
and a swan, and whole bushel of barley!
- And some mini donuts!
(Tom humming along to music)
- Um, can we get married?
We're in love.
- Nobody asked for a goose,
you take that right away!
- Aw, now somebody's sweater
is gonna have a big flaw!
- You put your feather in before the wool?
Hmm.
- With this wool will I clothe you.
- With these teeth will you bite me.
- With this barley will I nourish you.
- Oh, he's making Chex party mix.
- Ladies and gentlemen, the
magic of Ulysses S. Grant!
- The Sampo!
Sampo!
- Sampo means flavor!
- Now give me
the fire that burned in the clouds!
- How dare you!
Don't mention that!
- It's dirty!
- You want the Sampo?
That is the only fire I can forge it in.
It has to be the heavenly flame.
- Is it hot in here?
- I wonder if this is some trick,
to deprive me of the heavenly fire.
- But we won't have much use for that
if he makes the mill!
Give him the fire!
- We'll be able to have
as much flour as we want without grain!
- And we'll be able to have salt!
- And we'll be able to
make silver and gold!
(all clamoring)
- My spin doctors.
- Go and fetch the heavenly
flame for him, then.
- But someone stay here
to answer the phones!
- Boy, she's really broken
through the glass ceiling, huh?
- Yeah.
(Tom singing along to music)
- Yeah, yesterday's soap.
We're trying to get rid of it.
- Oh, it looks like Caligula in here.
- How would you know that?
The soup has a escort?
- Good soup.
(grunting)
- Here, ditch this flaming skull for me,
I don't know how that got in there.
- Nice weight.
- Mm-hmm.
- Real good flame.
- Put all your idle people to work,
I'll need their help.
Tell them to work the bellows!
- You heard what he said!
- Saul Bellows, get to work!
- No, no, aw.
- Is it Sampo yet?
- Now, be careful, this plate is very hot.
- So how does this work?
- Hey, let me know when you need a break.
- Mark seven!
Mark seven!
Oh, mark seven, damnit!
- Riam trolls, working for you!
- Where's a friggin' Sampo,
(continues garbling)
- Uh, Steve, honey, why don't
you go get Daddy a beer.
- You said you'd make
the mill, where is it?
- The men can't make the fire hot enough.
- Sure, blame my department.
- Keep working, you sluggards!
Pump the bellows, make the flames leap up!
- We're doing our best, Mistress.
- He's got a cocktail dress on!
- Ah, it's not done, must have
been frozen in the middle.
- He's got delusions of grandeur.
- Hey, it's like urban cowboy.
- Oh, boy.
How's that beer coming, Stevie?
- Work harder!
Get the heat up!
Faster, faster!
- Get off, Todd, come on, I'm serious!
Come on!
- Oh, they think I'm working,
that's the beauty part!
- Woohoo!
Oh, I hate this infernal routine!
- Burn, baby, burn!
Disco Inferno!
- Oh, the guy on top
must be the shop steward.
- Will someone please get the phone?
- Kids come running for
the rich taste of Sampo!
(all scream)
- Be careful, that's nitric
acid, we don't have very much.
(all screaming)
- Oh, I hate this school lunch program.
- Water's considered a vegetable.
- This is why I don't make
Sampos except on holidays.
- Hey, can we help?
- You can help by setting the table.
- Sorry, Sampos off.
- Sampo!
- Ask for it by name.
- Eh, that's a Sampo, huh?
- Sampo!
- You know.
- Ray Nitschke?
- Do you get wafers with it?
- You don't get bleeding wafers with it!
- It's very impressive.
But how do I know it works?
- Well, you just plug
it into the wall outlet,
and turn it on.
- Let there be gold, and flour,
and salt!
- Of course, I recommend
the service contract.
- Still, I think it would
look better by the couch.
- Sorry I doubted your Sampo.
(men cheering)
- Boy, I thought there'd
be more people around
the gold part of this thing,
but the line's really
not that long, you know?
- This is what it would have been like
if Perot would have won.
- Oh, great, rock salt!
We'll never slip on the driveway again!
- Makes you think, don't it, honey?
- Nice to see them so happy.
- Yup.
- The manual's in the box, and, uh,
first upgrade's free.
- Now give us back Annikki.
- Oh, she's home already.
- Alright, I will give your
pretty sister back to you now.
- I must warn you, she's aged some.
- Wait, that's the wrong sister.
- Help yourself a heapin'
helpin' of sweet Annikki.
- Annikki!
- Do I know you?
- Lemminkainen!
- You're not as cute as I remember!
On a clear day...
- Annikki!
My little sister!
- Take that creature away from my palace!
- [Joel] Oh, killjoy.
- I want her gone with
all those nasty flowers!
- Don't worry, lady,
we're out of here, gosh!
- Oh hey, Missus, the
Sampo stopped working,
and we didn't get the service contract.
- Smash them, take them away!
- And I want them all inventoried, too!
- We don't want them here,
the evil stunning flowers!
- Man, I wonder what her
Myers-Briggs test was like.
- How were you ever able to rescue me
from that wicked creature?
- Well, I had to make this
boat all by myself, and...
- Hey, leave my sister alone.
- Your brother, Ilmarinen, made a Sampo,
and left it with the wicked witch,
in place of you.
- A Sampo?
- You mean one of those
big things that makes
gold and salt and stuff?
- Yeah.
- You mean the new '92 Sampo
- with the leather interior?
- [Annikki] And because of me,
he deprived our people of
their rightful treasure?
- I am returning to Pohjola,
and I shall recover the Sampo.
- No, Ilmarinen!
I am going back for it, now!
- No, well, I think a
better plan would be to go
back and get supplies--hey!
- Hey, he's got pure wool on,
he's gonna shrink right up!
(waves crashing)
- Try the cleaning power
of new Lemminkainen
in your rinse cycle!
- This is it, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Think so.
- Oh, really love the new Sampo!
No buyer's remorse here, witchy-poo!
- Who's hungry for salt?
- Oh, geez, I better plan this, let's see.
Oh, gotta take the Sampo, it's my dad's.
No, damn!
Sampo repair!
(clears throat)
Might I just pop in and grab my Sampo?
No, darn!
- Oh no, they really like it.
I was hoping they wouldn't
be getting into the Sampo,
no such luck.
- Mmm, a good heft.
- I caught you, you filthy wretch,
trying to steal my gold!
- No, I wasn't!
- Catch him!
Don't let him get away!
Find him and throw him in the machine!
- Hey Tony, come on,
it's me, your roommate!
- Monkey pile.
Phew, ugh!
That was a mistake.
- That was the chile relleno wind.
- Ew!
- Ouch.
- Who let the mist out?
It blinds me, so I cannot see.
Back into thy bag, mist, I conjure thee,
back into thy bag.
(Joel coughing)
- Why did thee even have the mist,
if it bugs thee so much?
- It's kinda like a giant
Neo-Synephrine bag, isn't it?
(witch screams)
- Ma'am?
- Where is the many-colored
dome of the Sampo?
- Ma'am, the dome is an
option that you did not order.
- After him, and bring him back here!
- Ah, I can never just sit
back and enjoy my Sampo!
(men groaning)
- Hey, it's nice out here!
- Ah, there he is!
- Miss America!
- Destroy Ilamiren!
Destroy Lemminkainen's boat!
Release them!
Let the winds rush over
and destroy this fiend!
- Fly, monkeys, fly!
- Oh, now why does this always happen
at 4:30 on a Friday?
- Lemminkainen bold, exciting and new!
- Aguire, the wrath of God!
- I'm gonna get a bigger boat, right?
Yeah, we're gonna get a
bigger boat, definitely.
- Make the witch a Sampo,
what the heck was I thinking anyway?
- Wind, with Matthew
Muldeen and Jennifer Grey.
- Now on video.
- Hey, it looks just like
the statue of Iwo Jima,
if you cross your eyes and get the poles
with all of those guys.
- Hold on Buck!
Hold onto the boat, Bucky!
- Anybody got any Dramamine?
(gagging)
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the Swedish Moses of soul.
- There's got to be a morning after...
- The boat is wrecked!
- Don't get short with me, dope!
- It's wrecked!
(all clamoring loudly)
- Yeah right, Madonna and her dancers
get along really good.
- You still can't let go
of the Sampo, can you?
Let it go, Sven.
- Um, Dad said I could use the car.
You got the keys?
- He will be coming home soon,
and I promise you I will dance with you
at your wedding feast.
- Oh.
Give me the good news now.
- Our father, who art,
Huh?
- Woe! Oh, woe!
Your brave son Lemminkainen
has met his death.
- It can't be true!
My son lives.
- Coo-coo, coo-coo, coo-coo.
- Oh, she is off the beam.
- I see a kidney.
- I do, yeah.
- Heathcliff! Catherine!
- Have pity on a mother's prayer.
Friend of the four winds of Heaven.
- Um, have we met?
- Can you tell me what's
become of my brave son?
- I have troubles enough of my own.
The men strip my bark for making baskets.
The children break my branches for brooms.
How should I know anything about your son?
- Geez, sorry I asked!
- Birch, birch, birch.
- Now get out of my office!
Miss Jenkins, I pay you
to screen these people!
- I see a past president
who shall remain nameless.
- Oh you mean,
- Chester Arthur.
- Hey, uh, lady!
I'm a nice big pine that
you could pray to, maybe.
Maybe?
- Tell me, old wandering road,
have pity on a poor mother's sorrow!
Do you know what happened to my son?
- Um, b-oh I'll put the
word out on the street!
Oh, I am the street.
- Excuse me, I'm kind of stuck in a rut.
- Mother Teresa, in a role
that will inspire you!
- You should have pity on me!
I am the road!
- I didn't appreciate what
Kerouac said about me!
- ...to find your wandering son.
- Oh, poor road.
You have everything, I have nothing!
- I have enough troubles of my own.
- Now I know what they mean when they say
the road goes on forever.
- Do you know how many times
men have trampled on me?
- She's praying to county
road D2, what does she want?
- How they make the hooves
of their horses kick me.
- What is it with the
inanimate objects today?
- Have you thought about praying to me,
God, the big G-meister?
- Dear Almighty refrigerator door,
oh.
- Oh glorious sun, you who look over all,
- Well, I do my best.
- Answer a mother's prayer.
Tell me where I can find
my son, my brave boy.
- Look for your son
- She's praying to a Mills brother!
- Far in the north.
In the cold and craggy
land of Pohjola.
- You should do voiceovers.
- He is a prisoner of the evil witch,
Louhi.
- At least he was as of last Wednesday.
- That's a Richard Diebenkorn painting.
I think.
- Oh, great north deciduous forest,
oh never mind.
- Ever eat a pine tree?
Many parts are edible.
(Crow humming)
- What? Hey!
Somebody took my minnows!
- Oh, I think I'll just skip some rocks.
- Oh, dead, bloated carp,
floating in the shallows,
oh.
- Hey, it looks like one of
those Hamm's Beer clocks.
- Sea wheat.
It's...
(imitates trumpet)
I hate Mondays!
- Now wipe your feet before
you come into Finland!
(Tom grunting)
- Morning.
(techno music)
This small mound is alive
with the sound of
- When Lemminkainen met Annikki.
- I pick myself up and dust myself off,
I start the day all over again!
- I can't believe it.
I'm David McCallum.
- Lemminkainen!
- No, I didn't get your flippin' Sampo.
- Oh, my son!
- Way to wreck the scene, Mom.
- Forgive me, dearest Mother.
- Okay.
- And you should forget me.
- I have no right to be happy,
for I have destroyed the Sampo.
- Jerk.
- Hey!
- [Crow] Hey!
- Did you get the Sampo?
- How's it going!
- [Crow] Where's the Sampo?
- We sure are excited about the Sampo!
Oh.
- I just wanted to hear how it
went with the Sampo, is all.
- How's the Sampo?
- An ashtray?
- Give me my sister back!
Here, I got one of these already.
- Sampo is no more.
- Well, I did bring the Sampo home game.
- It would cheer brave night,
- Hey! You're the road, aren't you?
- And you, my people, take heart!
- Time will come,
- [Joel] We've hit bottom.
as you will see.
When even this, the fragment of the Sampo,
will bring much joy and happiness
to the people of Kalevala.
- No, a lot of good that does them now.
- Yugh.
- Kalevala, come before us.
Kalevala, stand before us.
- La la la la la la.
- Kalevala, come before us.
Kalevala, stand before us.
- This is my favorite bit he does!
Watch this, it's good, hoho!
- Good Mistress!
Come quickly!
- Something's coming in
on the urinescope, sir!
- Evil Lemminkainen lives!
- Oh, you got some on my robe.
- Now, let my cloak
bear me far to Kalevala,
to destroy the people who live there!
- It's the Von Trapps!
- Yeah, out for their morning run!
- Oh, say, everyone, did
you hear there is no Sampo?
- Yeah, it's really too bad.
- No Sampo, eh? Bummer.
- Let us be gay, for he is a dickweed.
- I'm so glad it's a dry celebration.
It's so much more fun than
the kegger would have been!
- Failed to bring back the Sampo
- Sampo!
- We shall die of starvation!
(robots singing)
- What is this, Stalag 17 the musical?
- I think it's the Black Oak Arkansaw.
- Failure, failure,
he's such a failure, failure, failure.
What a real failure, failure, failure.
- Hey, it's Ravi Shankar.
- [All] Failure, failure,
- Really loser, failure.
(singing continues)
- Surrender Ilsa!
- Recon! Look out!
(imitating engine noise)
- I meant to do that!
- Marty Feldman, in a role
that won't surprise you.
- Failure!
He's such a stupid little failure!
- Oh, it looks like Rutherford B. Hayes
just got out of the sauna!
- Stupid, stupid little failure!
- Ugh, hand over the bride.
I can't wait all day.
- Well, here's the keys.
She's a little slow to
start in the winter,
just give her some gas.
- Wait, my dears!
Just wait till you see the
gift I've brought for you!
- Guess they shouldn't
have registered in Hell.
- We still think he's a failure,
- What? She's marrying the Yale crew team?
- Bad news, they wanna water ski.
- Our old slave ship?
You shouldn't have!
(children laughing)
- Hurry up, they're gonna consummate!
- Alright, hit it!
(imitates engine)
Hey, the kids look ripe!
'Bout ready to drop!
- Plump.
It's a nice day for a wet wedding.
- And you know, the
kids planned the wedding
all by themselves, and I think
they've done such a nice job.
We're just so lucky
that the rain held out.
- Mmm, yeah.
- I thought we were gonna get a limo?
- Sure beats fooling around
in a nice hotel, eh, Honey?
- Come on, kiss him!
Here comes the failure.
- You know, this is considered
a riot in Scandinavia.
- Wild.
- [All] He's a failure, la la la la,
What a loser, la la la la,
Total failure, total failure,
total failure, la la la!
(Crow continues to sing)
- You know, this is the kind of music
that Up with People rejected.
- Oh, they're gonna
honeymoon at a rest stop?
- Yup.
- [All] Total failure, total failure,
Failure, failure, la, la, la!
- Okay, that's fine!
Please disperse!
- Failure, da da da!
He's a loser and a chump!
Failure, failure, total failure,
What a loser, la, la, la!
- Okay, oh, that's for fun, huh?
- Are you with the bride or the failure?
- Huh! Check out this guy.
He looks like something you could buy
in a gift shop up north.
- Now, why is he wearing a
Hershey's kiss on his head?
- Hey.
Sup.
- Brando's here!
- [Crow] Brando!
- It's Brando!
- Hi, Mr. Brando.
- All rise, Santa is entering the lodge.
- What the hell is going on in here?
This is my room!
- Uh, just throw this on
the gift table, would you?
Didn't have time to wrap it.
- They never invite me to anything!
- May health and happiness be with you,
all the days of your life!
- Oh, no!
- He's drunk again.
- Uh-oh!
- Healthy with you, Vainamoinen.
You are kind to pay a visit
to our humble little cottage.
- Oh, thanks.
I see this coming in real handy.
- Heh heh, what am I?
I'm a moose!
- Grandpa, that's Aunt Essie's urn!
(imitates sputtering)
- Your beer is almost too
strong for an old man like me.
- Oh, coronary, oop!
- It's the jolly troll!
- Oh, she's calling the Batman!
- Maybe she's mad cause she
used to date Lemminkainen.
- Yeah, she's lots of
laughs, but not the kind
you'd settle down with.
- She's fine for junior
year, but you gotta move on.
- Ooh.
(women screaming)
- That was the night that the
lights went out in Finland.
- The sun is gone!
(cackling)
- Oh, looks like she's, uh,
dragging a muffler there.
- Evil times have fallen
on happy Kalevala.
- Come on, it's just a
circuit breaker, Grandpa!
- Wicked Louhi has come,
she's stolen the sun.
- Golly, he's really calm in a crisis.
- Mmm.
Sorry about the failure.
- Farewell, good friend.
- Fare thee well, kind mistress.
Fare thee well. Thank you.
- Uh, I had the cut crystal bowl
that the dip was in.
Well, we'll come back.
- Pff! Great wedding.
Get half a buzz on and then
sent home with a torch.
- There can be no happiness,
without the sun.
- Oh, come on, Kirsten,
I'm a night person,
I love it.
- Keep for me my kantele.
- Take a hit if you want to.
- Now, it can only remain silent.
I must not play on it,
unless the sun is up.
- Oh, Mr. Particular!
Everything's gotta be just right!
- Yeah, it looks like they're trying to
take back the night over here.
- No, I think it's a Melanie concert.
(doors whirring, clanking shut)
- [Voiceover] Ladies and gentlemen,
presenting in her one-woman show,
Gyspy!
- Here we go!
- Shhhh!
- [Joel] Oop, sorry.
- There's a big frontier
out there called life
I ain't nobody's daughter,
I ain't nobody's wife.
I'm gonna state my very own claim of land,
and you're gonna wanna know who I am.
I'm Gyspy!
Gypsy Rose Me!
Gypsy Rose, not you!
Not you!
Or you!
Gypsy Rose...
(wails loudly)
Me!
(applause)
- Alright!
- Gypsy, yeah!
- Thank you!
Oh, thank you very much!
You know, we're all traveling.
You, me, that little gold guy over there.
We're traveling on the
big trip of life, and,
sometimes it turns out,
we haven't packed the right clothes
for our own personal journey.
I've been struggling to make ends meet.
The social worker stopped by today.
We'll get by, somehow.
Thank you!
(applause)
Thank you, thank you.
I'm sick of fighting with you, boyfriend!
But I'm not going to walk out that door.
No, sir!
I'm going to run out that door!
(applause)
Thank you!
Thank you very much!
- She's a survivor!
- You bet!
You know, I've seen her before.
- Hey!
Is my act interfering with
your conversation, buddy?
(laughing)
You came three guys together, huh?
What, some sort of love
connection screw-up?
(laughter, applause)
Thank you!
Oh, thank you, thank you!
What a night, everybody!
But before I go, I wanna
tell you a little story.
A story about a gal,
who ran the higher functions
of a little satellite
in a synchronous orbit.
A gal,
that everyone thought was
perhaps a little slow,
a little naive, a little simple.
But let me tell you
something about that gal!
She had spirit!
She had guts!
And most of all, she had a huge heart.
That gal was on her journey, and,
when her luggage ended
up on another planet,
that gal picked herself
up, dusted herself off,
and wore the same outfit
two days in a row!
That plucky little gal...
Is...
Me!
Oh, thank you very much!
(applause)
Oh, thank you, thank you very much!
- We've got commercial sign,
I'll be right back on down to meet you.
- I'll be here all week, thank you!
(techno music)
- Hey, look, it's Skylab!
(whistling noises)
- Heheh, Mommy's back
and I've got presents.
- Now, open the bag and
release the blizzard!
May the North Wind bring snow
to blanket the land of Kalevala!
Forever!
- And may you stay forever young!
- Meanwhile, in Frostbite
Falls, Minnesota...
- We have some school closings today,
including Stockholm, public and private,
Oslo, public and parochial,
Helsinki Votech, Solomid junior high.
- Boy, that looks cold!
- Mm-hmm.
(all humming and singing)
On Plummus Bane, the annual
running of the goats!
(bleats)
- The Christmas that almost wasn't.
- It's not a fit night
out for man nor beast!
- The Day the Earth
became unseasonably cool.
- I guess everybody's gonna
blame me for this, too!
- Yeah.
- What? Oh, I thought I
caulked that thing, gah!
- It's like they moved
in with the Ingalls.
- Yeah, Little House on the Tundra.
- Geez, has to half and
half with her coffee.
Okay, dear, I'll wade through the blizzard
to get your half and half!
- The Shining.
- Actually, it looks kind of inviting!
- Moonlight in Vermont.
I'm gonna bury Gary in a pile of snow.
Doo doo doo.
- Merh, one little cup of coffee
and she's gotta have her
friggin' half and half in it.
- Walking in my winter underwear.
- Hey, a penny!
- Watch out where the huskies go
and don't you eat that yellow snow!
- Uh,
Oh, hey, Aunt Roadie, the
old grey goose is dead!
- Rosebuuud.
- Rip Taylor's outside.
- Come on, I wanna come in!
Cause it's cold outside, ha!
I got a big prop I want to show you!
It's funny!
- It's true, first day of
marriage is the hardest.
- Hey, here's your damn dinner.
- I suppose you want me to clean that now.
- I'm not the pheasant plucker,
I'm the pheasant plucker's son.
I'm only plucking pheasants till the
pheasant plucker comes.
- I know, dear, I know.
Um, not on the good bench.
- Honey, it's a Swanson frozen dinner.
Oh, what's the use.
- We'll call it Trudy.
- Wait, she's wearing an
embroidery hoop on her head.
- One word: annulment.
- I'm afraid the poor thing is dead.
- Oh, the Sampo could have saved it.
- Oh, shut up with that Sampo!
- Soon we will all be like this poor bird!
- She's turning into a steak on legs.
- I can't even see your eyes, Annikki.
- Without thinking olives.
- That's the worst thing
about this twilight.
- You're in the house,
take your bike helmet off.
- I can't even remember
what color they are.
Let me look in your eyes again.
- Look, she's Swedish,
I'm guessing they're blue.
(cries)
- Yeah, well I'm gonna eat.
- Honey, we got any
orange sauce in the house?
- Duck!
With orange, duck with
cherry, a duck surprise, haha!
Duck without orange or cherry.
- Ilmarinen!
- Hey, what's the deal
with your sister, man?
- Ilmarinen.
- Duh, hamburgers!
Oh, sorry, dozed off on the old anvil.
- This...
- Sucks.
- Cannot go on much longer.
You must make a new sun for us!
- I'll use the Sampo to make one!
Ooh, wait, we don't
have one, that's right.
- I will do what I can.
- Not as I do.
- Huh, Grandpa rioted and
got a week in the hole.
- The Great Escape: 30 Years Later.
(Tom hums)
- Hruh-hurr-uh.
Well, I'm turning in.
Big day.
(robots singing)
- Hmm.
Why are they so bummed out?
- Oh, they just saw Captain Ron.
- Personally, I like Kurt Russell.
I love The Computer Wore Tennis Shoes,
but that's just me.
- No, no, the sun's bigger!
- Yes, we recall it being
quite large, really!
- And it's got, it's got spots!
- Mm-hmm, yes.
- What are you doing, Ilmarinen?
- He is forging a new sun for us.
- It is futile.
- No, it's fusion!
- To try to forge the sun anew.
The one thing left is to
release it from prison!
- Well then, you come up
with your own ideas, man!
- Take up your swords!
Your swords and spears!
Vainamoinen will lead us to Pohjola,
and we shall fight a
battle to release the sun.
- Not so, Lemminkainen.
- Have a seat, Lem.
- Against the wizards of
Louhi you cannot prevail
with a sword.
Of what use are your swords
against their spells?
I will take all of you to Pohjola.
- A class trip?
- And each one of you must hold...
- A herring!
- In place of a spear,
- Oh.
- Or a blade,
- You're making this up, aren't you?
- A sweetly sounding...
- It's!
- Kantele.
- Or, I don't know, I'm just mad.
- A kantele?
- And if each of us carry one of them,
that's a thousand kanteles!
- [Vainamoinen] More than that.
- 1200 at least.
- And we have them, here in
these ancient pine trees.
We'll cut them down,
make the harps ourselves.
- Great, we spend the winter making harps.
- What are you looking at?
- Come, boys,
take all the boats down to
the shores of the frozen sea.
- Whatever.
- And you, women.
- Back me up on this one.
- You must take all your
jewelry of silver and gold,
all your earrings, all your bracelets,
- All your naughty things.
- And cast them into the
crucible of Ilmarinen.
He must have clear-sounding
strings for our kanteles.
- Yeah, first he has us making boats,
then we gotta do the horse,
now it's the kanteles, oh!
- This is the old guy's neck!
This is his head!
And this is his ribcage!
- Oh, he's got the Farrah Fawcett
exercise stick over there.
- Okay, who wants a hot dog?
Still gonna be a couple
minutes on the Brats.
- Just keep this burnt
one for me to nibble on.
- Honey, why don't you go get
those marinated steaks ready?
- Al, come on, don't be too careful.
We just gotta knock out these kanteles.
- Ow! Carved my own leg into a kantele.
- Hey, uh, anybody care
if I turn on the radio?
- Huh, can you believe it?
Two weeks ago we were in shorts out here.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
the Mormon Tabernacle Choir
and Mountain Boys!
- Crow, you are out there, man.
- Thank you.
- But German potato salad
takes a little longer.
- It's a boy!
(quacking)
(techno)
- Oh, well the ice seems safe.
We shoulda brought the pickup.
- Oh, golly.
- [All] Cigars, cigarettes,
cigars, cigarettes.
- We come bearing honey baked hams.
- Tell me, my seers and wizards,
- Okay, you're ugly and you smell bad.
- What have we here?
- It's an army of warriors from Kalevala.
- Kalalalala?
- They are coming this way!
And there's too many of them to count!
- The year my voice broke!
- Come on!
- [All three] We want
the sun! We want the sun!
- When kings go senile.
- I thought it was a costume ball!
- They're gonna launch
him from a catapult?
(imitates catapult)
- What weapons do they carry?
- Harps!
- I wonder, do they think they're
coming to a wedding feast?
- Ha, good one, your Hideousness!
- Liked it, liked it.
- Let's see.
Love, soft as an easy chair...
(clears throat)
- Take up your spears,
the ones pointed with shark's teeth.
- Ah, sure, as soon as this tune is over.
- Brandish your swords,
steeped in serpent's venom,
and kill every one of them!
- Uh, did you hear that, sir?
- Kill them all!
- You know, the music kind of
adds to the drama, actually.
- It does.
- It's all skate.
Everybody on the ice all skates.
- Stalingrad, the standoff dragged on.
- Don't listen to that music!
Wake up, cover your ears,
cover them up with your hands.
That terrible music'll kill us all!
- Yeah, well, we put up with your Kenny G,
you cow.
- Welcome to the Moody Bible
Institute, prayer hour.
- Uh, Grandpa, try another chord.
- He's doing self-indulgent jam!
- We must stop them!
Get your swords out.
Here's your knife.
- For once, I'm on her side.
- Use your arrows!
Unsheathe your broadswords.
Attack them, attack them!
- Argh, but I love a
Prairie Home Companion
anytime I can sit and listen, I love it.
- And that's the news from Lake Woebegone,
where the men are strong,
the women are good-looking,
and the children are above average.
Oh, Bush Thompson's gonna
come out with the band,
gonna do a medley of songs about cats.
Then Jeanette Pool will do some
cat sounds, and then another episode of
watching paint dry.
Then Claudia Schmidt'll come out, and
try and fill the gap in her teeth.
And Pat Donohue and Peter
Ostroushko are gonna favor us
with the story of the Swede
(snoring)
who didn't like meatballs.
Then, uh...
- Argh!
It's so hard to get
good trolls these days!
- Ah, ah, ah!
- Oh, it's a Mapplethorpe photo.
- Go forth, North wind, go forth!
Freeze the people of Kalevala!
Shroud them in the mantle of death!
(wind whistling)
- Don't look at it, Marion!
Don't look!
- I said, pump faster!
- Let's kick into our grand funk medley!
- Um, um, um, sir?
Um, maybe it's time to
break out the bagpipes?
- Ooh.
- I say,
I hear they call it Mariah!
- Well, whatever it is,
it's flippin' freezing!
- Yup.
- Okay, uh, do you have a plan B?
- Alright, new tune, everybody.
A one, a two, a one, oh, forget it.
(ice shattering)
- It's Patton!
- You do not belong in
this place of honor.
- 'Twas a rock and roll creation.
- The cream of wheat
stays with you all day,
and that's nice.
- Kinda lilting, isn't it?
- Go forth, my cloak,
to the army of Kalevala.
- Kalavalalala, right.
- And strangle those wires
- Yup, strangle, wires.
- Who still remain on their feet.
- And feet, right.
Okay, bye.
- Soundtrack by Spike Jones.
- Boing!
- Hey, throw me the cape, oof!
- Uh, uh, anyone wanna throw in here?
- This has gotta be embarrassing.
- Yeah, on top of the whole Sampo episode.
- Ha, ooh yeah.
- Cloak took advantage of me!
(men struggling)
- We thought the cloak might
try something like this.
We were prepared.
- Oh, it's ruined, cause it said,
"Hand wash only in cold water", so.
- Stupid cloak, stupid
dumb old jerk cloak!
Just snap-stupid.
- I'm all ears, sir, sorry about that.
- Now, Lemminkainen, do you see?
Now you may go in and set the sun free!
- Oh, may I?
- Ah, this thing here?
- Yes!
- For the glory of Kalevala,
I am going to release the sun
- from prison!
- [Crow] Oh, just do it,
and don't screw it up!
- Remember the Sampo, buddy.
- Oh?
What do you want?
Keep awaaaay, keep awaaay!
Ohhh, the pain, the pain!
- Oh, well, that makes it a lot easier.
- Hey, Mrs. Witch, can
your sun come out and play?
- Hey, you know, you don't
like the weather in Sweden,
just wait a minute, you know?
- Swede blanket Bingo.
- I'll take Sweden, wow!
- So they headed for
central Minnesota, you know,
to build Crystal, and Blaine and Fridley.
And they made bars, and
sought out church basements
for refuge.
- Oh, let's see if the Turglesons
want to have a luau tonight, eh?
- Yeah, that's a good idea.
- Welcome, Greg Allman!
- Hi.
- And welcome, Roger McGuinn!
- Howdy.
- This is the most emotion
ever expressed in Sweden,
you realize that?
- I did the sun thing okay?
Haha!
- Thank you, Leatherhead.
- [Robots] Hehehe, hehehe.
- [Vainanoinen] May there always be,
- It's you!
You brought the birds!
You're evil!
- It's the end of the world!
- [Vainanoinen] There will always be
love in the world.
- D'awww, okay.
- Lemminkainen and
Annikki will be back in,
The Forests of Secrets and Lies!
- Neat, huh?
- [Voiceover] Lemminkainen
was played by John Powers.
- Not very well, granted.
- [Voiceover] Annikki, by Nina Anderson.
- Donations are being accepted
at the Stockholm Spinal Research Hospital.
- [Voiceover] Louhi the
Witch by Ingrid Elheart.
- A woman?
- Yes, a woman!
- [Voiceover] Ilmarinen,
by Peter Sorensee.
- Know these faces, remember these names.
- [Voiceover] Vainomoinen,
by Elgin Tanner.
- James, at 92.
- If you see any of these people,
please, for their own sakes, turn them in!
- Well said.
- Finland, Finland, Finland.
(doors clanging shut)
- You know, Gypsy, I
just wanted to tell ya
how much I enjoyed your
one-woman show earlier.
It was so confessional,
there were times I actually
felt kind of uncomfortable.
- Oh, great.
You know, if you hadn't,
I would've felt I failed.
- Yeah.
- Well, I gotta go rinse some things.
- Okay, see you later.
(obnoxious whistling)
Hey!
What are you guys doing?
- [Tom] Guess!
- Um,
- [Crow] Give up?
- No, you're, uh,
you're the wind from today's movie.
- [Crow] Nice, simplistic answer, Joel.
But we've gone beyond that!
We are delicately wafting scents,
gently borne by the wind,
and caressing your rosy cheek.
- Okay.
- [Tom] For example, I'm
a lilac in the spring!
Aaaah!
- [Crow] I'm a slice of pie!
- Nice, creative idea.
- [Crow] Or I could be a pizza.
- [Tom] Oh, yeah, with
onions and a kind of
low-gradet budge sausage!
- [Crow] Sure, sure.
- [Tom] You know, I suppose
I could be the wind,
but I'd be the wind that
comes from your friend
who manages the Realto theater,
if you know what I mean.
- [Crow] I'm the stench of bitter failure!
- [Tom] I'm James Coco's
oldest pair of boxer shorts!
- [Crow] I'm Dick Butkus!
- Oh, okay, okay, you two,
I think it's time for us
to read a letter, okay?
Let's just...
- [Crow] Hey, what was that?
- [Tom] Aah! It sounded
like fabric tearing!
- [Crow] We're going down!
Mayday! Mayday!
- I'm just, no, I'm just,
I'm just opening the mailbag, okay?
- [Crow] Oh, okay.
- Here's a letter,
let's put that up on still store, Cambot,
and there's a picture.
This one comes from a Donna Sweeney,
- [Tom] Hello, Donna!
- [Joel] And she says,
"I just want to tell you
"that my husband Brian
and I are the biggest
"MST3000 fans, and have
been so for many years.
(robots crooning)
"Currently my husband
and I reside in Germany.
- Ah, Germany!
- "My husband is an army
bomb disposal expert.
"I am enclosing a photo of
their bomb disposal robot,
"and I want to let you know
"that he has been nicknamed Crow,
- [Robots] Huh?
- "in honor of Crow T. Robot."
- [Crow] Hey! Lemme see that.
- Wow, that's pretty neat.
No, I can't.
I think I should show this to Gypsy,
she's probably really like it.
- [Crow] Hey, hey, help us down!
I'd like to see that! Joel, Joel!
- [Tom] Can you give us a hand,
we'd really like to come down now!
- [Crow] Oh...
- [Tom] Joel, I, heh!
You might want to help us down,
cause we smell really good now.
I'm a T.J. cinnamon bun, mmmm!
- [Joel] Oh, I'm not, I'm not interested.
- [Crow] And I'm fresh applesauce!
Oh, he's gone.
- [Tom] Think he'll be back?
- [Crow] I don't know.
Hey, what's your bag smell like?
- [Tom] Oh, you don't wanna know.
(both shuddering)
- Frank, are you alright up there?
- [Frank] What do you care?
- Frank, I care a lot!
- [Frank] Then give me back my money!
- All you care about is money.
Well, maybe you need some time alone
to think about your priorities!
- [Frank] Woaaah!
- Oh!
(camera blips)
(dramatic synth music)
(trolls groaning)
- What's going to become of us now?